# Junyoung Park

Website: pjywang.github.io Email: pjywang@kaist.ac.kr

# Research Interests

I am generally interested in data analysis with unique geometric structures necessitating rigorous treatment. Much of my research focuses on **compositional data analysis**, including variable selection, dimension reduction, and predictive model development. I am also interested in the recent theory of kernel conditional mean embeddings, sufficient dimension reduction, and high-dimensional statistics.

## EDUCATION

#### Ph.D. Candidate in Mathematical Sciences

2018-2024

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Daejeon, Korea (Co)Advisors: Cheolwoo Park, Jeongyoun Ahn

## **B.S.** in Mathematics

2013-2018

Korea University, Seoul, Korea

## EXPERIENCE

### Research Assistant in Statistical Learning

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Cheolwoo Park and Jeongyoun Ahn

2021 - 2024

- Kernel methods, compositional data, dimension reduction, autoencoder clustering

#### Research Assistant in Algebraic Geometry

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Sijong Kwak

2018-2021

- Projective geometry, syzygies, applied algebraic geometry
- Extensive training in geometry, algebra, and analysis at the graduate level and beyond

#### Max Planck Institute for Mathematics in the Sciences

Leipzig, Germany

Visiting research student

Summer 2019

- Attended Summer School on Randomness and Learning in Non-Linear Algebra

# University Financial Engineering Association (U.FE.A)

Seoul, Korea

Team leader

2016-2017

- Led Master's-level financial engineering & mathematics studies
- Studied stochastic modeling and hedge (pricing) theory of various equity, interest rate derivatives

#### AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

• Presentation Award for Graduate Students, 2nd place, Korean Statistical Society (KSS)

2022

• The Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award, Calculus II, KAIST

Fall, 2020

- University Students Contest of Mathematics, Silver Awards, Korean Mathematical Society (KMS) 2016, 2017
- Presidential Science Undergraduate Fellowship, fully funded for 8 semesters

2013-2018

• The Korean Mathematical Olympiad (KMO) 2nd round of middle school division, Gold Awards 2009

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Park, J., Ahn, J., and Park, C. (2023), Kernel Sufficient Dimension Reduction and Variable Selection for Compositional Data via Amalgamation, In *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), pp. 27034-27047, PMLR (link).
- 2. Kang, I., Choi, H., Yoon, Y.-J., **Park, J.**, Kwon, S.-S., and Park, C. (2023), Frechet Distance-Based Cluster Analysis for Multi-Dimensional Functional Data, *Statistics and Computing*, 33(4), 75.
- 3. Park, J., Yoon, C., Park, C., and Ahn, J. (2022), Kernel Methods for Radial Transformed Compositional Data with Many Zeros, In *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), pp. 17458-17472, PMLR (link).

#### *In progress:*

1. Dimension Reduction for Compositional Data with Interpretable Compositional Outcomes (with Jeongyoun Ahn and Cheolwoo Park), partially appeared in my Ph.D. dissertation.

## Talks

• 2023 Winter Conference, the Korean Statistical Society Sungshin Women's University, Seoul, Korea 2023

- Title: Interpretable composition-to-composition dimension reduction via conditional covariance operator
- 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (postered) Honolulu, HI, USA

2023

- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- $\bullet\,$  2023 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society

2023

- Pukyong National University, Busan, Korea
- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- 2022 Fall KAIST Math Graduate student Seminar

2022

- KAIST, Daejeon, Korea
- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- 39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (spolight talk) Baltimore, MD, USA

2022

- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- Presented also at 2022 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society, Seoul (awarded, 2nd place)

## Teaching

- Teaching Assistant at KAIST (selected list)
  - Statistical Data Science Practice (DS516)

Spring 2023

- Probability and Statistics (MAS250)

Fall 2021

- Abstract Algebra I (MAS311)

Spring 2021

- Mathematical Statistics (MAS355)

Fall 2019

- Matrix Group Theory (MAS435)

Spring 2019

- · Gave a guest lecture on connectedness of Lie groups in English
- Abstract Algebra II (MAS312)

Fall 2018

 $\cdot$  Gave several lectures throughout the semester

# Computing Skills

- Python (for machine learning, statistics), R (for statistics), previous experiences with Matlab and C.
- Acceleration of optimization: experience in leveraging TensorFlow AutoGraph in my research.
- Parallel programming in R: foreach package, mclapply function in Linux environment.

## LANGUAGES

- Korean (native)
- English

# Hobbies

- Singing, better with playing guitar.
- Running, hiking, and climbing.

# REFERENCES

#### Cheolwoo Park

Department of Mathematical Sciences and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST

parkcw2021@kaist.ac.kr

## Sijong Kwak

Department of Mathematical Sciences KAIST sjkwak@kaist.ac.kr

# Jeongyoun Ahn

Department of Industrial & Systems Engineering and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST jyahn@kaist.ac.kr